Benjamin Franklin Papers Part 6 -- Letters to Franklin 1781-1782 Mss.B.F85inventory06
American Philosophical Society
- Letters to Benjamin Franklin.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, A.N. 1p.; Le Roy, Mme
    Writes to inquire about his health and says that his friends (herself and others) would like to pay him a visit that evening.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, A.L. 1p.; Le Roy, Mme
    Is very displeased with Franklin for letting her go away in the inclement weather the previous evening so late and keeping M. Le Roy with whom she wished to take supper. Has always tried to be agreeable to him, but will in future not expose herself to such a slight. Returns him his umbrella.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, A.N. in 3d P.; Le Roy, Mme
    Inviting Dr. Franklin and his grandson to dine and spend the afternoon at her house.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, A.N. in 3d P. 1p.; Le Roy, Mme
    Asking if he will introduce "La petite femme de poche" to M. and Mme. St. Auban.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, N. 1p. A. Dr. of N. 1p.; Helvétius, Mme
    Inviting Dr. Franklin to dinner.
    A.E. by Franklin: It gives him so much pleasure and happiness to see her and hear her speak that he cannot but accept such a precious invitation.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, A.N. in 3d P. 1p.; Le Roy, Mme
    Inquiring about an invitation which they had received from Dr. Franklin.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 before May 21; 1p.; La Loge des. Neuf Soeurs
    Noting that the honorary office of Venerable was unanimously bestowed on Franklin.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, L. 1p.; Martinet, Mathieu
    Released from prison in England, petitions for prize-money due him for several English vessels captured whilst he was on the frigate "Protector."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, L in 3d P. 1p.; John Oliver and Emanuel Miles. London
    Two American prisoners, residents of Dunkirk, France, confined in Clerkenwell prison, beg Franklin to obtain thier release.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1782]; A.L.S. 1p.; Monthigny, Gourdeau
    Desires Franklin to procure him employement in the American army, or the position of tax collector on one of their islands.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1782?]; L in 3d P. 1p.; Montréal, ----- de
    Went to America as Director of Military Hospital in the train of Rochambeau's army; the breaking up of this army makes him fear the recall of his commission; desires letter of recommendation to certain commercial houses in America.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1782?]; L in 3d P. 1p.; de Montréal
    Asks for letters of introduction to business houses in America which might employ him.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1782]; L in 3d P. 3p.; Musset, Veuve. L'Orient
    Begs Franklin to secure payment of her bill for board, lodging, etc., of two sailors from American frigates of war.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, c. 1782; L in 3d P. 1p.; Pignatalli, Comte de
    Informing Franklin that has had his first audience with the King and Queen as Ambassador Extraordinary of the King of Naples.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782; A.L.S. 1p.; La Rochefoucauld, Duc de
    Recalling Franklin's invitation to a subscription concert at his house on account of the expected presence of Lord and Lady Stormont; as the treaty is not yet concluded, Franklin may not care for an interview with the Ambassador.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, c. 1782; L in 3d P. 1p.; Messrs. François Romand & Sons
    Are sending one of thier sons to Boston with a large quantity of merchandise to dispose of. Request Dr. Franklin to give him a letter of introduction to some prominent merchant there.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1782]; A.L.S. 2p.; Romanier, -----
    Thanking Franklin for all his kindness to his brother and asking a continuance of his favor.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1782]; L. in 3d P.1p.; Rougemont, -----
    Asking Franklin to viser the due bill enclosed.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1782]; A.L.S. 1p.; Rowbottom, William. Nantes
    Pressed into the English army and sent to America; deserted twice and escaped to France; desires to pursue his trade of ship-joiner.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1782]; L. 3P.; Toner, David et al
    Petition from nine American sailors, who seized an English brigantine which was confiscated by the French authorities at San Domingo, begging Franklin to obtain the return of the vessel or its value to them.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1778?]; L. 1p.; ______, _____
    Making inquiries as to the fate of M. [de] Mauduit Duplessis, a French officer, who entered the American army two years before.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, c. 1782; A.L 1p.; ----, ----
    Thanking him for his kind attention to the writer and his wife. Inquiries about his health and asks when he will come to see them.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1782?]; L. 1p.; -----,-----
    Informs him of the great losses he sustained during the war, and asks him to induce Great Britain to make some compensation to the American sufferers.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782?; A.L. 1p.; [Bradel, Jean Baptiste ?]
    Sends explanation of the medal [struck in honor of the capitulations of Saratoga and Yorktown.] Thinks he has understood what Franklin wished, simply a description of the events designated on it. x
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1782.]; A.L. 1p.; -----,-----
    Inviting Franklin and his grandson to dine with him. Expects to have Count d'Estaing. Asks Franklin to invite M. de Chaumont also.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 before Aug. 29; N. 1p.; -----, -----
    Requesting a letter of recommendation to M. Duler, supercargo on the ship "Harmonie" bound for Charleston or Edenton.
  - to Beraud de Ciccati, Lt Col ----, 1782 March 2; Benjamin, Franklin
    Promising to send his letter by the first opportunity. L I p (In French)